I was right in not avoiding her... wasn't I?
No, maybe it was a mistake.
Because her body was extremely, and unreasonably, light.
That's right. For her, Senjougahara,
the thing called weight...
did not exist.
Even though it's the cultural festival, we are already third years.
There isn't much we have to do seriously.
Besides, preparing for the exams is also very important.
For starters, let's list some alternatives.
We'll get everyone to cast their votes from there.
How's that?
It's fine. It seems somewhat democratic.
Your tone is harsh as always, Araragi-kun.
Should I call you stubborn, or is it...?
Hanekawa Tsubasa, the class representative.
She is law-abiding, well-mannered, extremely serious, and highly praised by teachers...
The representative of all representatives.
Just for reference, what did you suggest for the cultural festival last year and the year before?
Ghost house and café.
And, as the vice-president, I'm discussing the plans for the cultural festival with Hanekawa.
Hey, we have a student named Senjougahara in our class, right?
Senjougahara-san?
What about her?
Well, I'm just concerned about her.
Doesn't she always take leave from school since her body is weak?
I was wondering if she would even be participating in the cultural festival.
Hmm?
Besides, don't you agree that the name Senjougahara Hitagi is very strange and fascinating?
Senjougahara... that surname comes from the name of a place.
No, not that.
Rather, I meant her other name...
Senjougahara's given name is... Hitagi, correct?
Is there anything as strange as that?
"Hitagi" sounds like civil engineering jargon.
You sure know everything, don't you?
It's not that I know everything.
I just know what I know.
How rare.
Huh?
Araragi-kun is actually interested in someone else.
No, it's not like that.
Boys always like girls that are physically ill.
Ah, seriously...
How disgusting.
Physically ill?
Ah, but is it really an illness?
Regardless, what kind of a person is Senjougahara?
You should be more informed regarding things about her, shouldn't you?
Haven't the two of you been in the same class for three consecutive years?
Now that you mention it, we have.
Well, she's an honors student with a clean record.
Her grades are also pretty good.
I guess.
But I've only been in the same class as her for a month.
Indeed, I don't know her that well.
Golden Week lies within that month.
Golden Week, huh?
Eh? What about Golden Week?
It's nothing.
Carry on.
Oh, let me think...
Senjougahara-san... She doesn't speak much.
She doesn't seem to have any friends, either.
It must be due to her illness.
She was livelier and more full of spirit during junior high.
Speaking of junior high... Did you go to the same school as her?
Yeah.
She was really beautiful, good at sports, and the star of the track team.
As such, I heard many rumors...
What rumors?
That she's a very good person who treats others kindly.
Apparently her father is an important figure in a foreign-owned business.
She also seems to be living in a luxurious house.
Despite that, she has never shown arrogance.
She sounds superhuman.
Maybe it's inappropriate to say this, but Senjougahara-san...
What?
...looks more beautiful now than she did in the past.
A fragile existence.
"A fragile existence"?
Ah, I just remembered something.
Oshino told me to come over.
Oshino-san?
What happened?
It's just to help with... some stuff at work.
Hmm?
Hanekawa, can I leave the rest to you?
If you promise to make up for it later, I'll agree to end it here today.
You shouldn't keep Oshino-san waiting for too long.
Thanks.
Say hi to Oshino-san for me.
What were you discussing with Hanekawa-san?
Don't move.
Ah, I said that wrong.
You're free to move, but doing so will be very dangerous.
That's what I meant to say.
Curiosity... such a thing can be compared to cockroaches.
It swarms around the secrets that one doesn't want others to know.
It's truly frustrating.
Hey.
What is it?
Is your right side feeling neglected?
Well, why didn't you say so?
Though I must say, I was careless.
I really did not expect a banana peel to be at such a place.
You found out, didn't you?
That's right.
I don't have any weight.
Despite what I said, I'm not entirely weightless.
According to my body shape and height, my average weight should be in the range of 45 kg and above.
But my actual weight is...
...5 kg.
It happened after I graduated from middle school and before I started high school.
I met a crab.
It completely stripped me of my weight.
It's forgivable even if you don't understand it.
I'm only telling you this since I find it inconvenient for you to stick your nose into it any further, Araragi-kun.
Araragi-kun.
Hey, Araragi Koyomi-kun.
Tell me. What should I do if I want to render you unable to reveal my secret?
What should I do for myself...
...
in order to make you swear not to reveal it, even if you were to be tortured and interrogated?
What can I do to disable your mouth?
Regardless, what I want is silence and ignorance.
If you promise to stay silent and feign ignorance,
nod your head twice, Araragi-kun.
Any other action, including staying still, will be taken as an act of hostility.
And I shall act immediately.
I see.
Thank you.
You didn't scream.
Impressive.
I'll let you off just this once.
You...
Then, Araragi-kun...
As of tomorrow, you are to ignore me, got it?
I'm counting on you.
She's exactly like a monster.
Ouch...
But it's all right.
This type of injury means nothing to me.
My, Araragi-kun?
Hanekawa.
You're still here?
Didn't you need to hurry over to Oshino-san's place?
Hanekawa, do you like bananas?
Eh? Well, I guess I don't hate them.
Besides, they're nutritious.
If you insist on asking whether I like them or not, then yes, I like them.
No matter how much you like them, never eat them in school.
Huh?
It's okay to eat just one...
...but toss the peel in the hallway, and I definitely won't forgive you!
Just what exactly are you talking about, Araragi-kun?
Ah, hey, Araragi-kun!
You can't run in the hallways!
I'll report this to the teacher!
How ridiculous.
No, I suppose I should say, "I'm surprised," right?
I never thought that you'd be able put up such resistance after suffering from that sort of treatment.
Senjougahara.
All right, I get it.
I understand, Araragi-kun.
Let's have a war.
No, no.
I don't want a war.
You don't?
That's no fun...
What do you want, then?
I just thought...
that I could be of help to you.
Help me?
Stop joking. What can you possibly do?
You only need to shut your mouth obediently and not say anything.
I consider acts of kindness as hostility, too.
Your wound...
It's gone...
You... How can that be...?
Oshino... Oshino-san?
That's right. Oshino Meme.
Thanks to him, I became a human again instead of a vampire.
Though, there are still some aftereffects from when I was undead.
Hmm... Oshino Meme?
The name sounds very moe.
You'd be deceiving your feelings if that's what you're anticipating.
He's a 30-year-old uncle.
Ah, I see.
But he must have been moe when he was young.
Don't use an approach like that to visualize real people.
Speaking of which, do you understand what "moe" and "character" are?
They're part of general education.
A character like me is known as a tsundere, am I correct?
It'd be more fitting to refer to you as a tundra.
My butt hurts. It feels numb.
My skirt is also crumpled.
That's not my problem.
Don't push your responsibility. Be careful or I'll chop it off.
What part will you chop off?
By the way, where did you put your bag?
You're empty-handed.
I've stored my textbooks in my school locker.
Besides, when your body conceals stationery, you don't need a bag.
Ah, I see.
Without going empty-handed, I cannot fight freely in the event of an emergency.
I'll hold that stationery for you.
I'll guard it. Hand it over.
Oshino is said to be a weird uncle.
Even so, he's still my savior.
I can't let him meet someone dangerous, so let me keep that stationery.
Now you tell me?
You set me up, didn't you?
I get it.
Take good care of it.
Why, you...
Don't be mistaken.
I haven't let my guard down against you.
What do you mean, "you haven't let your guard down"?
Keep this in mind.
My five thousand barbarous comrades
are stationed to attack your family if they don't receive contact from me every minute.
It'll be all right. Don't worry.
You say a minute is enough to do it?
You think I'm some kind of a boxer?
Both of your sisters are still in middle school, aren't they?
This way.
What are you doing? Don't even think that I'm thanking the likes of you.
I'm not.
Rather, you should be the one who's thankful.
I don't understand that.
That stapler wound... In order for it not to be obvious...
...I intentionally stapled it from the inside rather than from the outside.
That's the same logic as "to hide the wounds, hit the stomach instead of the face."
It's for the good of the attacker, not the victim.
Well, regardless, it seems that I was worried over nothing.
Right...
If I said, "Being undead is just so convenient," would you be offended?
Right now... I wouldn't.
Oh, is that so?
Besides, I'm no longer undead.
It's just that my wounds heal faster.
Apart from that, I'm just like an ordinary person.
Araragi-kun, I'll say this once more.
What?
Perhaps it's difficult to tell from my clothes,
but my body might not actually be worth the price you'd pay for committing a crime.
How should I say...? On the whole, you seem to be overly self-conscious.
In other words, you have quite a persecution complex.
How rude.
Be that as it may, there are things you should and shouldn't say.
So you knew?
I must say, I'm impressed that this Oshino person manages to live in such a decrepit building.
Yeah, he's a rather weird person.
But it's said that he specializes in people like you and me.
Oh, Araragi-kun.
You're finally here.
What's this, Araragi-kun?
You have a different girl with you today?
Shut up.
Don't set me up as some cheap person.
Hmm.
Nice to meet you, miss.
I'm Oshino.
Nice to meet you, too. I'm Senjougahara Hitagi.
I'm classmates with Araragi-kun.
I heard some things about you from him.
Ah, I see.
Oshino, around two years ago, this girl―
Please refrain from referring to me as "this girl."
Then, how should I address you?
Senjougahara-sama.
Senjougahara-sama~!
Don't use such a robotic tone.
Say it properly.
Senjougahara-chan.
Ouch!
You trying to gouge my eyes out?!
Rude comments are an eyesore.
What type of equal exchange is this?
Copper: 40 g. Iron: 25 g.
Nickel: 15 g. Concealing embarrassment: 5 g.
Add 97 kg of bad intentions, and you've got my statement.
That was mostly just bad intentions!
Just so you know, that concealing embarrassment part was a lie.
You just deleted the element that you shouldn't delete!
In any case, before we start...
Who is that kid?
Ah, don't mind that.
One without shape or shadow...
A child which doesn't have a name and doesn't exist.
No, no, Araragi-kun.
I gave her a name yesterday.
She worked pretty hard for me during the Golden Week
Eh? You gave her a name?
What is it?
I named her Oshino Shinobu.
Heart under blade.
This name really suits her, right?
Her surname will be mine.
Sounds great.
As I was saying, what exactly is this kid?
Weren't you listening? She's nothing.
The remains of a vampire.
The leftovers of a beautiful demon.
Saying it like that is useless, but it can't be helped.
I see.
It's nothing major.
Then I will forget it.
I heard you can help me?
Help you?
No can do.
The only one who can save you is yourself, miss.
I've been fed that stage line by five other people.
All of them were frauds.
Don't tell me you're just like them, Oshino-san?
You sure are feisty, miss.
Did something good happen to you?
Well, anyway...
If you don't tell me, there's nothing to be said.
I keep secrets well. It'll be all right.
Ah, let me give the gist of it.
No need for that, Araragi-kun.
I'll do it myself.
Senjougahara...
I'm able to do it myself.
Weight Crab.
Weight Crab?
Yes, it's a myth from the mountains in the Kyushu region.
According to different areas, Weight Crab is also known as Mind Crab or Heavy Crab.
Furthermore, God of Emotions is another way of saying it.
It's a pun on kani and kami, which are crab and god.
But... why Kyushu?
The place doesn't have much unique significance.
If the right conditions are met, it shall emerge there. That's all there is to it.
In this case, it doesn't necessarily have to be a crab.
There are also myths that they are rabbits.
And... though I'm not talking about Shinobu-chan, there are also myths that they were beautiful girls.
It's like the face of the moon.
Well, since you say you met a crab, miss,
this time it must be a crab.
What exactly is it?
Its name is of no value to me.
The name is very important.
I also mentioned it earlier.
It could originally be a god, rather than a crab.
I mean, it diverged from God of Emotions to become Weight Crab.
You are one of the fortunate ones amongst the unfortunate.
Why do you say that?
Gods are everywhere.
They are everywhere, but nowhere.
Before you became like this...
it was beside you, yet not beside you.
It's an ambiguous question and answer, isn't it?
This is a Shinto matter. Oh, maybe it's Shugendou?
Don't be mistaken, miss.
You didn't become like this as a result of something.
It's only that the perspective changed a bit.
Perspective?
What are you trying to say?
I'm saying that your "oh, so pitiful" look makes me unhappy, miss.
Eh, still so calm, are you?
I thought you were a spoiled little miss.
Why would you think that?
A majority of the people who encounter Weight Crab are like that.
It's not something you can meet because you want to.
Interference with this god is uncommon.
Uncommon interference?
It merely exists there.
It won't come true if you don't anticipate it.
Rather, I don't want to dive too deep into this matter.
Regardless if it can be done or not, I understand.
If you wish to regain your weight, I can help you.
Besides, Araragi-kun recommended me to you.
You will help me?
I'm Karen.
I'm Tsukihi.
About the worker ants,
You really said it.
The majority of them actually don't work!
The majority, 80%, don't work!
So I'll be pushing my work off onto others!
What's up with you?
The worker ant has a name that just sounds pushy in the first place!
But I guess you can't exactly call them slacker ants,
And I've got a riddle for next week's preview.
Riddle!
"Heat & Beat" refers to me but...
It refers to you but...
What is the name of the "&" symbol?
The problem is that the riddle itself isn't hard. It comes from its phrasing.
The correct answer is obviously "ampersand!"
I get it!
Next time:
Hitagi Crab Part 2.
You can only watch it if you solve this riddle.
But then no one will see it.